A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Staff Subject Files, Elizabeth Campbell FA1468
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Staff Subject Files, Elizabeth Campbell
1992-1996
Rockefeller Archive Center
Campbell, Elizabeth C.
Ford Foundation
FA1468
1 Cubic Feet 3 boxes (2 letter document containers and 1 half letter document container)
Biographical / Historical
Elizabeth Campbell started her career as a program officer in the Rural Poverty and Resources program at the Ford Foundation in 1991. She was with the Foundation for 12 years, rising to director of Community and Resource Development. After restructuring at the Foundation, her title changed to senior director and later deputy to the vice president for Asset Building and Community Development.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains program officer notes and other correspondence regarding early thoughts, design, selection, and meetings of the Rural Development and Community Foundations Initiative (RDCFI).
Related Materials
Related Collection: (FA702) Ford Foundation records, Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS), Office of the Vice President, Senior Director, Office Files of Elizabeth Campbell
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into one series:
1. Rural Development and Community Foundations Initiative, 1992-1996
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transferred to RAC in 2018 by the Ford Foundation and ingested by RAC as Accession 2018:068.
Ford Foundation; Poverty -- Rural; Rural poverty and resourses; Community foundations
- Rural Development and Community Foundations Initiative, 1992-1996; 1
  Scope and Contents
  References to Grant Nos. 949-0003, 930-1085, 930-1082, 930-1081, 930-1083, 930-1084, 920-1394
  - Rural Development and Community Foundations Initiative (RDCFI) Key Documents (2 folders), 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Rural Foundations Initiative (RFI) - Recommended Grant Action (RGA) (2 folders), 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Rural Development and Community Foundations Initiative (RDCFI) Round II, circa 1992-1996 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Rural Foundations Initiative (RFI): Selecting Round II Participants (4 folders), 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 6-9)
  - Rural Foundations Initiative (RFI): Other Direct Inquiries (Other community foundations), 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Rural Foundations Initiative (RFI): Other Funders, 1993-1996 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Rural Foundations Initiative (RFI): Southern US Philanthropy, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Rural Foundations Initiative (RFI): Post-Selection Contact People, 1994-1996 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Rural Foundations Initiative (RFI): Early Thinking/Planning - Helen Monroe, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Rural Foundations Initiative (RFI): Early Thinking/Planning - Puerto Rico Community Foundations Meeting/Statewide Community Meeting/New Hampshire Community Foundation Meeting, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Rural Foundations Initiative (RFI): Early Thinking/Planning (2 folders), 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
  - Rural Foundations Initiative (RFI): Phase II - A. Orienting Round II, B. Ideas/Round I, Going, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Rural Foundations Initiative (RFI): Wider Audiences, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Rural Foundations Initiative (RFI): Rural Economic Policy Program (REPP) Role (Key Contributions - Institutes, Memos, etc.), 1993-1996 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Rural Foundations Initiative (RFI): Trustees Meeting, 1993 December (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Rural Foundations Initiative (RFI): Learning (Raw Material) (4 folders), 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 22-25)